Finding Aid of the Lisbon Area Neighborhood Development Corporation Records, 1999-2013
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Lisbon Area Neighborhood Development Corporation Records, 1999-2013
Lisbon Area Neighborhood Development Corporation
UWM Manuscript Collection 351
5 cubic ft. (5 boxes)(electronic records amount???)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
Electronic and physical records of the Lisbon Area Neighborhood Corporation (LAND). The collection documents how LAND acquired grants and implemented programs to improve the neighborhood surrounding Lisbon Avenue located on the north side of Milwaukee's inner city. The collection includes meeting minutes, grant proposals, budget and census data, resource and social events for residents, and property rehabilitation reports. Also included are digital images of the LAND programs and events.
The Lisbon Area Neighborhood Development Corporation (LAND) was a nonprofit organization that was founded in 1988 to address the neighborhood problems around 35th Street and Lisbon Avenue. LAND’s services included economic and community development through the rental of commercial property, home repair programs, and community organizing. LAND partnered with organizations, institutions, and business in the area to improve the neighborhood. LAND’s community organizing included working with residents to host neighborhood clean-ups, beautification projects, community meetings to address residents’ issues and concerns, and community events to provide education and resources.
Most of the physical and electronic records are progress reports on property improvement and community organizing programs dating from 2004-2013.
The files are organized by series, alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
Administrative/Restriction Information
Portions of the collection are restricted according to Title 5 of the United States Code, Section 552a.
Contents List
- Lisbon Area Neighborhood Development Corporation, 1999-2013, UWM Mss 351
    - 1. Subject Files, 1999-2013, Campaigns and Programs
      - Crime and Drug Prevention, 2005-2008 (Electronic Campaigns_and_Programs\, Electronic Crime_and_Drug_Prevention_2005-2008\, Electronic \)
      - Economic Development, 2004-2011 (Electronic Campaigns_and_Programs\, Electronic Economic_Development_2004-2011\, Electronic \)
      - Education, 2008-2011 (Electronic Campaigns_and_Programs\, Electronic Education_2008-2011\, Electronic \)
      - Neighborhood Improvement, 1999-2012 (Electronic Campaigns_and_Programs\, Electronic Neighborhood_Improvement_1999-2012\, Electronic \)
    - Community Development Block Grant
      - General Administration, 2006-2012 (Electronic Community_Development_Block_Grant\, Electronic General_Administration_2006-2012\, Electronic \)
      - Monthly Reports, 2008-2013 (Electronic Community_Development_Block_Grant\, Electronic Monthly_Reports\)
    - Correspondence, 2004-2013 (Electronic Correspondence\)
    - Crime Prevention Through Environmental Design, 2007-2009 (Electronic Crime_Prevention_Through_Environmental_Design\)
    - Executive Director Reports, 2009-2012 (Electronic Executive_Director_Reports_2009-2012\)
    - Flyers, 2004-2012 (Electronic Flyers\)
    - LANDFARE, 2009-2012 (Electronic LANDFARE\)
    - Local Initiatives Support Corporation, 2009 (Electronic Local_Initiatives_Support_Corporation\)
    - Logos, 2009 (Electronic Logos\)
    - Meeting Agenda and Notes, 2007-2013 (Electronic Meeting_Agendas_and_Notes\)
    - Minor Home Repair
      - Activity Reports, 2008-2010 (Electronic Minor_Home_Repair\, Electronic Activity_Reports_2008-2010\)
      - Grant Application, 2009 (Electronic Minor_Home_Repair\, Electronic Grant_Application_2009\)
      - Letter to Residents, 2007 (Electronic Minor_Home_Repair\, Electronic Letter_to_Residents_2007\)
      - Monthly Narrative, 2007-2010 (Electronic Minor_Home_Repair\, Electronic Monthly_Narratives_2007-2010\)
      - Reports, 2009-2010 (Electronic Minor_Home_Repair\, Electronic Reports_2009-2010\)
    - Mission Profile Services, 2004-2012 (Electronic Mission_Profile_Services\)
    - Neighborhood Property Data, 1999 (Electronic Neighborhood_Property_Data\)
    - Project Activity Reports, 2007-2013 (Electronic Project_Activity_Reports\)
    - Resident Engagement Community Forum, 2005 (Electronic Resident_Engagement_Community_Forum\)
    - Spaulding Place, 2004-2006 (Electronic Spaulding_Place\)
    - Special Economic Development, 2004 (Electronic Special_Economic_Development\)
    - Thirty-seventh Street, 2007-2012 (Electronic 37th_St\)
    - Twenty-eighth Street, 2008-2009 (Electronic 28th_St\)
    - UWM Community University Partnership
      - Back to School for Adults, 2009-2010 (Electronic UWM_Community-University_Partnership\, Electronic Back_to_School_for_Adults_2009-2010\)
      - Programs and Initiatives, 2008 (Electronic UWM_Community-University_Partnership\, Electronic Programs_and_Initiative_2008\)
      - Soil Testing, 2013 (Electronic UWM_Community-University_Partnership\, Electronic Soil_Testing_2013\)
    - Walls Project, 2008-2009 (Electronic Walls_Project\)
    - Washington Park Partners, 2004-2007 (Electronic Washington_Park_Partners\)
    - West North Avenue Advancement Association, 1999-2000 (Electronic West_North_Avenue_Advancement_Association\)
      - 2. Images, 2005-2013, Clean Up and Neighborhood Walk, 2013 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Cleanup_and_Neighborhood_Walk_2013\)
      - Community Dialogue with Gwen Moore, 2010 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Community_Dialogue_with_Gwen_Moore_7-14-10\)
      - Crime Prevention Through Environmental Design, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic CPTED_Neighborhood_Beautification_Project_39th_St_7-27-09\)
      - Giving Tree, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Giving_Tree_12-9-11\)
      - Homsource, 2006 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Homesource_11-9-06\)
      - Housing Program, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Housing_Program_1-7-09\)
      - Jones Island Water Plant Tour, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Jones_Island_Water_Plant_Tour_10-25-11\)
      - Holiday Party, 2010 (Electronic Images\, Electronic LAND_Holiday_Party_2010\)
      - LANDFARE, 2009-2012 (Electronic Images\, Electronic LANDFARE\)
      - Milwaukee Theater and Parade, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Milwaukee_Theater_and_Parade_2009\)
      - National Night Out Thrid District Police, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic National_Night_Out_3rd_District_Police_7-27-11\)
      - Neighborhood Cleanup, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Neighborhood_Cleanup_6-15-11\)
      - Neighborhood Walk, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Neighborhood_Walk_8-1-12\)
      - Prepared Readiness Workshop Youth, 2011 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Prepared_Readiness_Workshop_Youth_Env_Education7-25-11\)
      - Ready Set Go, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Ready-Set-Go_3-27-09\)
      - Social Gathering, 2010 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Social_Gathering_2010\)
      - Soil Testing Project, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Soil_Testing_Project_2009\)
      - Thirty Eighth Street School, 2007 (Electronic Images\, Electronic 38th_st_school_service_learning_5-23-07\)
      - UWM Back to School, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Back_to_School_UWM-MATC_5-18-09\)
      - Urban Waldorf and Metcalfe, 2007 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Urban_Waldorf_and_Metcalfe_SL_2007\)
      - Valentine Banquet, 2005 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Valentine_Banquet_2005\)
      - Walls Project, 2009 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Walls_Project_c_2009\)
      - Westside Academy and Fourtieth Street Cleanup, 2008 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Westside_Academy_and_40th_St_Cleanup_11-20-08\)
      - Westside Academy Service Learning, 2008 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Westside_Academy_Service_Learning10-10-08\)
      - Willie Hines, 2005 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Willie_Hines_2005\)
      - Youth Environmental Project, 2012 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Youth_Environmental_Project\)
      - Youth Project, 2010-2012 (Electronic Images\, Electronic Youth_Environmental_Project_2010-2012\)